CUONG T. DONG-SI

1618 Coraltree Pl, San Jose, CA 95131 dongsi.tuecuong@gmail.com (408)-646-0077

Website: http://tdongsi.github.io

Summary

- Experienced in designing and developing of **automated** testing tools and frameworks, written in Java and Python.
- Experienced in software testing, test automation, and test methodologies. Experienced in test development to achieve **portable** tests for various platforms and operating systems.

Skills

Languages: Java, C/C++, Python, Perl, Matlab, SQL, XML, XQuery, HTML.

Java stack: JDBC, Guava, Swing, JCommander, SLF4J, SWTBot, JUnit, TestNG,

Selenium, Apache Ant, Maven, Gradle, JMeter, RestAssured, JMockit.

Other Lib.: ANTLR, Boost, OpenCV, Eigen, Numpy, Matplotlib.
OS: Windows, Mac OS, CentOS, Ubuntu, SunOS, HP-UX.
Database: SQLite, MySQL, Netezza, Vertica, Cassandra, Hive/Hadoop.

Tools: Eclipse, IntelliJ, PyCharm, Visual Studio, Git, SourceTree, Perforce,

Jenkins, Confluence, JIRA, Trello, Splunk, Chef.

Work Experience

Software Engineer in Quality II, Intuit Inc.

12/2014 - present

- Develop and automate test cases for backend infrastructure and services in QuickBooks Online and Small Business Group ecosystem.
- Design and implement test frameworks to facilitate automated unit and functional testing in **Big Data** projects. Work with developers and data analysts on project requirements to make informed testing decisions and develop/evangelize appropriate test solutions.

Recent Projects and Achievements:

- Designed and implemented test plans for QuickBooks Online ecosystem's **Data Mart** projects, verifying business analytics requirements and functionalities implemented and validated.
- Implemented a test automation framework to facilitate automated unit/functional testing of **SQL scripts**, verifying Extract-Transform-Load (**ETL**) processes between data sources (e.g., Netezza, Hive, HDFS, Vertica), and validating data consistency and integrity.
- Achievements: Three successful releases of Data Mart with different analytic use cases, approved and used by business analysts and data scientists. Two Intuit Spotlight Awards for demonstrating Intuit Values "Learn Fast" and "Deliver Awesome".

Software QA Engineer, Objectivity Inc.

7/2012 - 12/2014

- Developed and automated test cases, maintained and executed test suites for company's database products, Objectivity and InfiniteGraph, and their various utility tools.
- Designed and implemented frameworks for automated performance testing. Worked with developers to make informed testing decisions and develop appropriate test solutions.
- Reviewed Java codes and enforced good practices for more robust and flexible Java API.

Selected Projects and Achievements:

- Designed and implemented test plans for measuring data ingestion performance of graph database InfiniteGraph in distributed multi-client settings. Set up and configured a network of eight Linux and Windows hosts with OpenSSH. Fully automated performance tests using Python scripts, in which multiple Java test applications are compiled and ingest data simultaneously from multiple remote hosts.
- Designed and developed an automated test suite for testing Java byte code injection tools, including a custom Java parser (based on ANLTR) to verify correctness of decompiled byte codes after injection.
- Developed **generic-based** JUnit tests for database-backed Java collection classes, based on Guava library. 5000+ JUnit tests effectively added into nightly test suite within a month.
- Developed functional tests for Talend data connectors that convert data from MySQL and Cassandra databases to Objectivity databases.

Additional Experience

Graduate Student Researcher, University of California, Riverside

- 9/2009 4/2012
- Designed and implemented sensor fusion algorithms for accelerometers, gyroscopes, and cameras, with applications targeted for smartphones and driverless car navigation systems.
- Implemented sensor-based navigation algorithms, based on probabilistic models and statistical inference methods, using C++ and Matlab. Designed and implemented pluggable sensor simulators for verifying and benchmarking performance of those navigation algorithms.
- Proposed and implemented various numerical algorithms for problem solving, including convex optimization techniques, Gauss-Newton algorithm and its variants.
- Achievements: Innovative algorithms for vision-aided inertial navigation, published at 2011 and 2012 ICRA conferences.

Research Software Engineer, National University of Singapore

8/2006 - 7/2009

- Worked in driverless car projects, a collaboration effort of multiple Singaporean industrial research labs, managed by Defense Science Organization (DSO), Singapore.
- Designed, implemented and evaluated computer vision algorithms for visual sensor modules.
- Designed and implemented an adaptive machine learning algorithm to identify drivable road surface from stereo images, by building statistical models of road appearance.
- Achievements: Three innovative visual sensor modules, presented at 2008 IROS and SMC conferences. Linux drivers for Windows-native IEEE-1394 cameras.

Education

Master of Science, 2009 - 2012, University of California, Riverside.

Bachelor of Engineering, 2002 - 2006, National University of Singapore, Singapore.

Honors & Awards

- Intuit Spotlight Award [August 2015]: for demonstrating Intuit Value "Deliver Awesome".
- Intuit Spotlight Award [March 2015]: for demonstrating Intuit Value "Learn Fast".
- IEEE ICRA Student Travel Award [2011, 2012], by IEEE Robotics and Automation Society.
- Dean's Distinguished Fellowship [2009], by University of California, Riverside.
- Singapore Scholarship, by Singapore Ministry of Foreign Affairs [2002-06], full tuition scholarship for undergraduate study, awarded to the top students of ASEAN nations.
- Dean's List, Faculty of Engineering, National University of Singapore [2002-04].
- Champion, IEEE All-Singapore University Tech Quiz [2005, 2006].
- First Prize, Vietnam National Physics Olympiad for Universities [2002]
- Merit Prize, Vietnam National Physics Olympiad for High Schools [2001]